# Killian Jochen McShane

# Machine Learning Engineer

killian.jmcshane@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/killianmcshane github.com/killianmcshane killianmcshane.github.io (+44 7821745056

Graduate of Computer Science with Artificial Intelligence (First Class with Honours) at The University of Liverpool.

Proficient in Python, R, Java, SQL, and functional Haskell programming languages with industry experience in machine learning, software development and data analysis with tools including TensorFlow, Apache Ant, SQL Server, Power BI, and Tableau.

#### **Education**

#### BSc (Hons) Computer Science with Artificial Intelligence The University of Liverpool

09/2018 - Present

First Class

### Career

#### **Machine Learning Engineer**

Health Data Research UK (Summer Placement)

07/2022 - 09/2022

Liverpool

- Developing predictive regression models to improve treatment of patients struggling with epilepsy.
- Developing predictive machine learning models to improve outpatient appointment-booking efficiency.

## Data Analyst & Machine Learning Engineer

The Walton Centre NHS Trust 10/2021 - Present

Liverpool

- Developing predictive machine learning models for clinical and patient flow with Python for statistical data analysis.
- Providing actionable insight to recommend opportunities and improvements through real-time data analytics dashboards with SQL Server & Power BI.

#### **Customer Service Representative**

The Royal Bank of Scotland

10/2017 - 03/2018

Belfast

- Teamwork, exceeding KPI expectations and preventing escalations was key in this high-pressure environment.
- Asked pertinent questions to empathetically deliver aid and successfully resolve issues quickly.

#### **Data Analysis Spring Internship**

FM Environmental

04/2015

Newry

- Analysed and processed friction and fluid calculations.
- Relayed insights from data analysis with Excel to aid engineers in their decision making.

## Languages

• English

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

German

Professional Working Proficiency

#### Skills



### **Achievements**

Founder & President of The Data Science and Artificial Intelligence Society at The University of Liverpool

I manage the society. My leadership involves chairing meetings, attracting funding, and managing relationships with stakeholders.

University of Liverpool Leadership Programme (2021)

Attended the university's leadership programme to boost my leadership potential and develop my professional skills.

BT Young Scientist Boot Camp (2015)

Selected for and won the competition. Lead a team of 5 individuals through the development lifecycle of a new product.

#### **Interests**

Boxing	Runni	ng Mat	hen	natics
Deep Learning		Big Data		Crypto & Blockchain

## **Projects**

Dissertation Project: A.I. for Political Ideology Classification (Python, Google Colab)

Using Google's BERT natural language processing machine learning model and social media APIs, I web-scraped a dataset of political comments and was able to classify users by their political leaning.

Automated Build Deployment & Testing (Java)

Build deployment using Apache Ant, Java, XML build files, and JUnit.

Short-term Stock Price Prediction Web-app (Python, JS) Stock price prediction using an LSTM Neural Network, Twitter's API, and natural language processing, sentiment analysis of Tweets.